Guide to the Stanford Energy Lectures
Stanford University Libraries.
- Stanford Energy Lectures
  - Philip S. Schmidt, Consultant, EPRI. OPPORTUNITIES FOR EFFICIENCY GAINS IN THE ELECTRIFICA TION OF INDUSTRIES., 1981 Nov 30; 150; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - T.J. Connolly, Sullivan Marsden and Ralph Samuelson, Stanford University. ANGTS: ALASKAN NATURAL GAS TRANSPORTATION SYSTEM., 1982 Jan 11; 151; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - William Schumacher, Director, Energy Economics & Resources Dept., SRI International. ANGTS IN THE CONTEXT OF U.S. GAS SUPPLY IN THE LATE 80's., 1982 Jan 18; 152; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Randolph Deutsch, Principal Counsel, California PUC and Daniel Gibson, Assistant General Counsel, PG& E. SOME INSTITUTIONAL AND LEGAL RAMIFICATIONS OF ANGTS., 1982 Jan 25; 153; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Ricbard Gilbert, Prof. of Economics, Univ. of California, Berkeley. WHAT DO WE DO IF WE LOSE THE PERSIAN GULF?, 1982 Feb 1; 154; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - James L. Plummer, President, QED Research, Inc. AN OVERVIEW OF THE SUPPLY VULNERABILITY PROBLEMS., 1982 Feb 8; 155; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Donna Downey; }lichael Lipset; Robert Steele, Regulatory Analysis & Management, SRI International. REGULATORY REFORM TO RESOLVE AIR QUALITY- ENERGY CONFLICTS., 1972 Mar 1; 156; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - George R. Offen, Project Manager, Acurex Corporation. ENVIRONMENTAL PROBLEMS IN SYNTHETIC FUELS PRODUCTION., 1982 Mar 8; 157; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Prof. Thomas J. Connolly, Mechanical Engineering Dept., Stanford University. THE UTILITY OF THE UTILITY AS FLAK CATCHER., 1982 Apr 5; 158; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Gidali Gutner, Electricite de France. THE FRENCH NUCLEAR ELECTRICITY PROGRAM., 1982 Apr 12; 159; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - J. Jones, E. Kinderman & D. Wilhelm, SRI International. THE ROLE OF BIOMASS IN FUTURE U.S. ENERGY SUPPLIES., 1982 Apr 19; 160; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Ethan Thorman, Windfarms, Ltd. WIND ENERGY AT THE ECONOMIC CROSSROADS., 1982 Apr 26; 161; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - E.H. Warren, Senior Economist, Jet Propulsion laboratory. THE SOLAR ALTERNATIVE - AN ECONOMIC PERSPECTIVE., 1982 May 3; 162; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - David Teece, Graduate School of Business, Stanford University. OPEC BEHAVIOR & WORLD OIL PRICES., 1982 May 10; 163; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - J. Michael Gallagher, Assistant to the Vice President, Research & Engineering, Bechtel Group, Inc. THE OUTLOOK FOR COAL PRODUCTION- IN THE UNITED STATES., 1982 May 17; 164; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Thomas Connolly, Mechanical Engineering Dept., Stanford University. NINE YEARS OF ENERGY CRISIS., 1982 Oct 4; 165; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Denis Hayes, Regents Professor of Innovation & Entrepreneurial Development, U.C. Santa Cruz. POST REAGAN ENERGY PLANNING., 1982 Oct 11; 166; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Edgar A. De Meo, Manager of Solar Power Systems Program, Electric Power Research Institute. SOLAR AND WIND POWER - STATUS AND OUTLOOK., 1982 Oct 18; 167; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Prof. Stephen Kline, Mechanical Engineering Dept., Stanford University; James Rifkin, Author, Entropy - A New World View. THERMODYNAMICS AND SOCIAL POLICY: A DEBATE., 1982 Feb 25; 168; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Herbert Kitschelt, Lecturer, University of Bielefield, F.R. Germany. CAN THE U.S. PLAN AND IMPLEMENT AN ENERGY POLICY?, 1982 Nov 1; 169; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Bertram Wolfe, Vice President, Nuclear Fuels & Special Systems, General Electric Co. CAN THE NUCLEAR OPTION BE REVIVED?, 1982 Nov 8; 170; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Milton, Searl, Electric Power Research Institute. THE ELECTRICITY - GNP RELATIONSHIP., 1982 Nov 15; 171; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Chauncey Starr, Vic Chairman, Electric Power Research Institute. THE MYOPIA STRATEGY FOR ELECTRICITY., 1982 Nov 22; 172; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Mason Willrich, Vice President, Corporate Planning, Pacific Gas & Electric Company. LONG-TERM PLANNING RESULTS 1982 - 2002., 1982 Nov 29; 173; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Thomas J. Connolly, Mechanical Engineering Dept., Stanford University. IN THE WAKE OF TMI., 1983 Jan 10; 174; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Roger D. Bourke, Jet Propulsion Laboratory. METHANOL: ITS POTENTIAL ROLE IN THE CALIFORNIA ENERGY SCENE., 1983 Jan 17; 175; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Arthur H. Rosenfeld, Lawrence Berkeley Laboratory. PROGRESS IN ENERGY EFFICIENT BUILDINGS., 1983 Jan 14; 176; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Paul Slovic, Decision Research Inc. PERCEPTION AND ACCEPTABILITY OF RISK FROM ENERGY SYSTEMS., 1983 Jan 31; 177; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Mitchell R. Wool, Acurex Corporation. THE PROJECT DEVELOPMENT FOR A100-MEGAWATT PHOTOVOLTAIC POWER PLANT FOR SACRAMENTO., 1983 Feb 7; 178; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Thomas Neville, Vice presi den t, Co rporate Develcipment; Natomas Company, BUSINESS PLANNING IN AN UNCERTAIN OIL MARKET., 1983 Feb 14; 179; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Elizabeth Pate-Cornell; Industrial Engineering Dept, Stanford University. RISKS AND DECISION PROCESSES IN THE PUBLIC SECTOR., 1983 Feb 28; 180; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Thomas J. Connolly, Mecha nica l Engineering Dept., Stanford University. LESSONS LEARNED AND NOT LEARNED FROM THE ENERGY CRISIS., 1983 Apr 4; 181; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Robert J. Budnitz, President; Future Resources Associates, Inc., Berkeley, CA. THE CHANGING RELATIONSHIP OF REACTOR REGULATION TO REACTOR SAFETY., 1983 Apr 11; 182; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Ralph L. Keeney, Woodeard-Clyde Consultants. A DECISION ANALYSIS OF ONE ELECTRIC UTILITY'S CAPACITY EXPANSION PLANS., 1983 Apr 18; 183; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - David Cohan, Decision Focus Inc. A DECISION FRAMEWORK FOR AMBIENT AIR QUALITY STANDARDS., 1983 Apr 25; 184; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Hillard G. Huntington. Engineering-Economic Systems Dept., Stanford University. THE IMPACT OF ENERGY PRICE SHOCKS ON THE U.S. ECONOMY., 1983 May 2; 185; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Warner North, Principal, Decision Focus Inc. ADECISION FRAMEWORK FOR ACID DEPOSITION., 1983 May 9; 186; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Anthony V. Nero: Co-Leader, Building Ventilation & Indoor Air Quality Program, Lawrence Berkeley Laboratory. EXPOSURES TO INDOOR AIR POLLUTANTS: THE CASE OF RADON., 1983 May 16; 187; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - George D. Sauter, Program Manager, Safety Assessment, Electric Power Research Institute. NRC's PROCESS FOR REGULATION OF NUCLEAR PLANTS., 1983 May 23; 188; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Thomas J. Connolly, Mechanical Engineering Dept., Stanford University. OVERVIEW OF TECHNOLOGICAL DEVELOPMENTS OF THE ENERGY CRISIS PERIOD., 1984 Jan 16; 189; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - John S. Gunz, Senior Energy Services Engineer, Pacific Gas & Electric Company. RECENT ADVANCES IN NATURAL GAS END-USE TECHNOLOGIES., 1984 Jan 23; 190; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Shelton Ehrlich, Progr am Manager, Electric Power Research Institute. FLUIDIZED BED COMBUSTION OF COAL., 1984 Jan 30; 191; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Edwin M. Kinderman, Manager, Energy Planning; SRI International. NEW ENERGY UTILIZATION TECHNOLOGIES AND THEIR IMPACT., 1984 Feb 6; 192; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Professor Robert H. Eustis, Mechanical Engineering Dept., Stanford University. THE STATUS OF MAGNETOHYDRODYNAMICS IN THE U.S. AND THE WORLD., 1984 Feb 13; 193; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Mitchell R. Wool & Robert Spencer, Acurex Corporation. CENTRAL STATION PHOTOVOLTAIC POWER GENERATION., 1984 Feb 27; 194; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Richard K. Pefley, Professor: Mechanical Engineering Department, University of Santa Clara. ALCOHOLS AS GASOLINE SUBSTITUTES., 1984 Mar 5; 195; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - James I. Davis, LIS Program Director, Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory. LASER ISOTOPE SEPARATION., 1984 Mar 12; 196; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
- THE ENERGY CONTROVERSY: SOFT PATHS UNDER FIRE
  - UPDATE ON THE SOFT ENERGY PATH. Amory and Hunter Lovins., 1983 Apr 5; 2000; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - BRITTLE POWER. Amory and Hunter Lovins., 1983 Apr 6; 2001; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - ECONOMICS OF THE SOFT AND HARD PATHS. Prof. James Sweeney, Chairman, Stanford Institute for Energy Studies., 1983 Apr 12; 2002; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - WHAT'S COUNTABLE VS. WHAT COUNTS: ARE WE ASKING THE WRONG QUESTIONS? Denis Hayes, Former Director Solar Energy Research Institute., 1983 Apr 14; 2003; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - THE SOFT THINKING OF SOFT ENERGY PATHS. Bertram Wolfe, Senior Vice President, General Electric., 1983 Apr 19; 2004; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - NUCLEAR POWER AND NUCLEAR WAR. Michael Shuman, Director, International Disarmament Forum., 1983 Apr 21; 2005; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - ENVIRONMENTAL LIABILITIES OF SOFT ENERGY PATHS. Rene Males, Electric Power Research Institute., 1983 Apr 26; 2006; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - ENVIRONMENTAL ADVANTAGES OF SOfT ENERGY PATHS. Peter Gleick, U.C. Berkeley Energy Resources Group., 1983 Apr 28; 2007; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - ENERGY SYSTEMS IN BRAZIL. Aldo DaRosa, Electrical Engineering Dept. Stanford University., 1983 May 3; 2008; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - BRINGING SOfT ENERGY PATHS HOME. Jeff Harris, Senior Researcher, Lawrence Berkeley Laboratories., 1983 May 10; 2009; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - IMPLEMENTING SOFT ENERGY PATHS IN INDUSTRY. Harry Whitehouse, founder, Pacific Sun Company, 1983 May 12; 2010; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - APPROPRIATE TECHNOLOGY: A PHILOSOPHY Of DESIGN. Moose Hydeman & Tom Strand, Stanford University., 1983 May 17; 2011; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - BUILDING THE SOFT PATH IN THE PACIFIC NORTHWEST, Ralph Cavanagh, Atorney, Natural Resources Defense Council., 1983 May 19; 2012; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - THE FUTURE Of UTILITIES. Amory Lovins and Rene Males., 1983 May 24; 2013; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - NATIONAL ENERGY POLICY. Edward Teller, Hoover Institution., 1983 May 26; 2014; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)